Guide to the Martin Gardner Papers SC0647
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Subject files, Series 2
  - Combinatorics, 62 folder(s)
    - Weighing Problems [1 of 2], 1963-1984 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Many different weighing problems, including many false-coin problems, and mathematical analysis of problems.
      2 false coin puzzles from Emmet Duffy, along with cardboard calculators for each (and the original 12-coin problem) & instructions for use. (Calculators in separate folder.)
      Tanner, Leslie
    - Comb. Die Problems [2 of 2], 1963-1997 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      "The False-Coin Problem - a Colorful Approach", by Uri Leron, Technion Preprint MT443, 1979
    - 12 Coins, 1955-2001 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Variations, references.
      Solutions using words (12 different letters).
      Riecker, Carl Jr.
      Wiley, Roland
    - Median Algebra (& Cards) (Craige Schensted), 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Long letter from Schensted that develops aAgebra of Medians, discusses its relationship to Boolean Algebra & Calculus of Propostions, and gives a couple of card tricks based on it.
    - Stable Marriage, & College Admissions Problem, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Original article (by Gale & Shapley), plus MG notes from Gilman's lecture.
    - The 21 "IDOO" Problem, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      IDOO = Isolated Diamonds, Order One (in MacMahon Squares.)
    - The 9-Piece Subset of MacMahon 3-Color Squares (Torus), 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Using the 9 MacMahon pieces that show all 3 colors, match all edges toroidally.
      Analysis of puzzle and game.
    - Finite Projective Planes, 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      2 articles, MG notes.
    - Empirical Formulas to which Calc. Finite Difs May be Applies, 1961-1991 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      3-color cubes
      Coloring of sides, faces of figures.
      Tetrahedra.
      Paths in Square City Blocks.
      Intersecting lines.
      Dissecting lines with points, plane with lines, etc.
      "Region Count for Straight Line Cutting of Flat Figures", by W. Funkenbusch & R. Odendahl (typescript)
      Mostly MG notes and calculations, plus some articles.
    - Pell Equation, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
      "Pell's Equation - A Tool For the Puazle Smith", by Mogens Esron Larsen (typescript)
    - Counters (Place or Move) (Cards, Etc.) [1 of 2], 1959-1985 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Slide & Jump puzzle (Leap Frog)
      Some peg jumping games.
      "Pegboard Games", by D. G. Tabta, Mathematical Teaching Pamphlet No. 13, 1967
      Hanky Panky (Forming piles).
      Color exchanges on 2-D boards
      ... and many more similar puzzles & games
      Kaplan, Philip
    - Comb. Die Problems [2 of 2], 1961-2002 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Penny-dime problems (permuting the order)
      Gombert, Jan Martin
      McNear, John
    - Sliding Penny Puzzles, 1995-2002 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Alternating Coins OoOoOo & Variants, 1960-1998 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Paper on Penny-dime probmes, by Gombert(typescript)
      Analysis, articles, MG notes.
      Bergerson, Howard
    - The Russian Pebble Problem, 1992-2000 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Murray, Jason
    - Dividing the Cake [1 of 2], 1967-1992 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      MG notes, references.
      Many algorithms for fair division, both in letters and articles.
      Saemundsson, Th.
      Balinski, M.L.
    - Dividing the Cake [2 of 2], 1992-2002 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Many more articles and algorithms.
    - Switching Puzzles, 1987-1989 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      2 articles: reversing trains, and Dewdney article.
    - Firing Squad Problem, 1965-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Synchronization problem with finite state machines.
      "The Firing Squad Problem", by W.F. Lunnon, 1970 (typescript)
    - Busy Beaver Problems, 1981-1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      5-state Turing machine to print maximal no. of 1's.
      Gallimore, Nicholas
    - Postage Stamp Problem, 1978-2000 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Least amount that cannot be made with at most t stamps, each one valued at one of k denominations.
      Rogers, Douglas
    - Pantactic, 1965-1993 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      "Phagic Squares", by Ian Stewart, ~1972 (typescript).
      "Pseudo-Random Sequences and Arrays", by F.J. MacWilliams and N.J.A. Sloane (typescript).
      Astle, Brian
    - Ising Problem, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      1 article (by Harary) + 1 page MG notes.
    - The Circular Ruler, 1973-1982 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      "On the Set of Distances Determined by the Union of Arithmetic Progressions", by F.R.K. Chung & R.L. Graham (typescript).
      James, David
    - Checkers & Go are P Space Hard (& Chess results), 1978-1981 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Costas Arrays (2D "Rulers"), Golomb & Taylor, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      2 Golomb articles (one with Taylor)
    - The Condom Problem, 1977-1989 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Vardi, Ilan
      Lipton, Richard
      Ghijsen, Jacques
    - Ferry (Crossing) Problems, 1961-1997 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Many rivere crossing problems, analysis, MG notes, etc.
    - Error Correcting Codes [1 of 2], 1950-1976 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Many articles, preprints, reprints, etc.
    - Error Correcting Codes [2 of 2], 1976-1999 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Guess A Number Game, 1972-1990 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Mediocrity
      Bulls & Cows (numberic Mastermind) (Moo)
      Silverman's Game
      Guess a Number - With Lying
      Toetjes Problem
      Eachus, Joseph
      Hawkins, David
    - Ulam's Guess a Number with Lies, 1974-2001 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Point-Set Coloring, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Self Avoiding Walks, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Bay Restaurant, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Jeep Problem, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Pancake Problem, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      Analysis by Leslie Upton
    - Paper Fold (Andy Liu), 1999 (Box 26, Folder 20)
      "Group Folding and Groups Unfolded", by Andy Liu (typescript)
    - Rolling Cubes, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Computers, 43 folder(s)
    - Computer vs Hand Proofs (Experimental Math), 1978-1994 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Several articles discussing computer proofs, especially in reference to 4-color theroem, mostly from a philosophic perspective
      Tymoczko, Thomas
      Swart, Edward
      Boas, R.P.
    - History - Electronic Calculators, 1964-1995 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Mostly newspaper & popular science magazines
    - Influence on Math, 1977-1989 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Discrete Mathematics, algorithms
    - Early Mechanical Devices (& New Hardware), 1973-1993 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Napiers Bones, Babbage, Adding machines, etc.
      Package (but ot item) of "Consul", the Educated Monkey, a calculator
      Williams, Michael
      Luebbert, William
    - Fluidics, 1960-1998 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      Some articles (SA & others)
    - Automation, Cybernetics [1 of 2], 1948-1965 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      Many articles (newspaper, popular science) on automation, its' advantages & its' dangers
    - Automation, Cybernetics [2 of 2], 1938-1993 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Collection of 1952 SA articles on automatic control, because the book based on them cut the articles and the pictures
    - Analog Devices, 1984-1985 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      2 SA articles by Dewdney
    - Teaching Machines, 1960-1963 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Computer & Video Games, 1974-1994 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Several (mostly popular) articles
    - Pocket Calculators, 1972-1981 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      Several articles, popular & technical
    - Pocket Calculator Problems, 1965-1980 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      Various ideas for calculator problems, many by MG
      Calculation a square root
    - Inverted Words, 1974-1979 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      ... on a calculator
      "Dictionary and Games For Pocket Calculators", by David, Sarah, & C. Peter Rosenbaum, 1975, 22p (typescript)
    - Calculator Tricks & Stunts, 1973-1983 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      Chinese Remainder Theorem
      ABCABC
      Many calculator magic tricks
      Lyons, L. Vosburgh
      Altman, David
      Neale, Bob
    - Pocket Calculator Games, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Set of problems from the HP-65 Users Club (1975)
      Subtraction game from Lynn Yarbrough
      Yarbrough, Lynn
    - Endpaper (NYT) (Pocket Calculator, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Notes & suggestions fro "Endpaper" column for the New YOrk Times
      Collins, Glenn
    - Dynamic Programming (Bellman), undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
      SA article on Control Theory, by Richard Bellman
    - The L.E.D. & L.C.D. Readouts, 1969-1976 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Various ways to write numerals and letters in grids
    - Computer Poetry (& Relation to Literature, etc.), 1971-1983 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      3 articles on computer verse
    - Supercomputers (nonorganic), 1958-2000 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Various articles, mostly popular science magazines & newspapers, on progress in supercomputing design & types of supercomputers
      "The Cosmological Limits on Computation", by Frank Tipler, 85pp (typescript)
    - Parallel Processing & Coming Supercomputers, 1983-1996 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Articles, mostly popular
      Also "Fifth Generation"
    - Information Retrieval -- HGW's World Brain, 1960-1998 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      H.G. Wells
      Many articles, technical and popular
    - Computer Art & Graphics [1 of 2], 1966-1996 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      Including various artists, and Tex
      Lurker, Ernst
      Geckeler, Siegfried
      Badler, Norman
      O'Brien, James
      Lambert, Frank
    - Computer Art & Graphics [2 of 2], 1980 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      Folder & press release on artist Enrique Castro-Cid, and exhibition at Lowe Art Museum
    - Word Processors, 1981-1985 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      3 articles, 2 on authors switching to word processors, one on loss of corrected manustripts to history
    - Molecular Computers (Nanotechnology), 1982-2001 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      Lots of articles, technical & popular
      Regis, Ed
    - Neural Neet Approach (Connectionism), 1987-1996 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Game Programs (General), 1998 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      Just 1 page, pointer to SA special on mind
    - Bridge Program, undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
      1 photocopy of bridge article, that computer programs can't play bridge well
    - Computer Simulations, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      1 article, from Discover magazine, Oct. 1989
    - Computer Crime (& Sabatage), 1976-1999 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      Lots of articles, on crime, viruses, worms, etc.
    - Optical Computers, 1989-1998 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "Virtual Reality" - Cyberspace, 1989-1993 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Lots of popular artticles, about virtual reality, art, Jaron Lanier, "Neuromancer", etc
    - Hypertext, 1992-1993 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Several newspaper articles
    - DNA Computing, 1995-1996 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Popular articles
    - Genetic Algorithms, Artificial Life, 1989-2000 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Mostly articles
    - Digital Libraries, 1995-2000 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      2 articles (Lipkin, Science News, & NYT Magazine, Burdick)
    - Email & Publishing, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      2 articles, C&EN and TIME
    - Java Language, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      1 article, American Scientist, by Brian Hayes
    - Computer Proofs, 1996-1997 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      2 newspaper articles & 2 magazine articles (Nature, Science News)
    - Reverse Computing, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      1 newspaper article
    - Grading Machine!, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      1 article "New Word Order", by Clive Thompson, Lingua Franca, about software that could grade essays
    - Quantum Computers! (& Code Cracking), 1992-2001 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      Many articles on quantum computers and quantum crypology
  - Diophantine, 13 folder(s)
    - Diophantine Prob's [1 of 2], 1960-1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      "Diophantine Equations and Electronic Calculators", by Rufus Isaacs, 46pp (typescript)
    - Diophantine Prob's [2 of 2], 1976-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      "Tiling the Square With Rational Triangles", by Richard Guy, 1988, 57pp (typescript)
      "Faltings Plus Epsilon, Wiles Plus Epsilon, and the Generalized Fermat Equation", by H. Darman, 1999, 16pp (typescript)
      Schoeder, Manfred
    - Heron Triangles, 1971-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Integral Tetrahedron & Hexahedroa, 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Baker, Gerald
    - Helbert's 10th, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Sacerdote, George
    - Mordell's Conjecture, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Euler's Conjecture - & Counter-example, 1966-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Rectangle-with-border Problem in 2 & 3 Space, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Sleator, Daniel
    - The "Integral" Brick, 1970-2001 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Morris, David
    - Archimedes Cattle Problem, 1965-1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - The Rational 7 (was 6) Points (unsolved Problem), 1970-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Honsberger, Ross
    - The 6 Problems Involving Pairs of Figurate Numbers, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      "On Some Diophantine Equations{", by Saburo Uchiyama, 1984 (Lecture Notes)
    - Crossed Ladders, 1962-1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      ApSimon, H.G.
      Hunter, J.A.H.
  - Dr. Matrix, 15 folder(s)
    - Mozart, 1992-1995 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      "Counting the Notes: Numerology in the Works of Mozart, Especially Die Zauberflote", by I. Grattan-Guinness, 1991, 31pp (photocopy)
      Karhausen, L.R.
    - On "23", 1993 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      "On the Synchoronicities of the Number 23", by Loren Goldner, 1993 (typescript)
    - Numberology - Misc., 1961-1997 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      Lots of articles (newspaper and other) on numerology
      Many notes for columns
    - 1/137 Fine Structure Constant, 1972-1998 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      "A Quantal Hypothesis for Hadrons and the Judging of Physical Numerology", by I.J. Good, 1989, 55pp, Tech. Rep. No. 89-13, V.P.I.
    - Numerology & Individual Numbers [1 of 2], 1963-1998 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      Lots of notes of individual number curiosities (mostly numbers 1-14)
    - Numerology & Individual Numbers [2 of 2], 1975-2002 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      15 and miscellaneous larger numbers
      Dickson, Paul
    - Numerology of Constants (Pi, e, Phi, Euler, etc.), 1959-2001 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Word Play Items, 1970-1994 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Many of the items are biblical
    - The Canadian Code Nickel, 1946-1977 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      "Victory" five cent Canadian coin, 1943 & 1944, with a message in International Morse Code around the edge
    - Ideas For Future Matrix Columns, 1976-1997 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      Republican presidents are prime
      Artificial language
      Computers
      Math art (Dr. M in SoHo)
      Creative Adventure - randomness, coincidences, etc
      Nuclear physicist - arrows of time
      Chess (& Fibonacci)
      St. Louis & catenary arch
      Gambling casino (with bar bets)
      Occult, Uri Gellar, EST, etc
      Thoughts on Matrix novel
      ... & misc. notes & articles, etc.
    - Dr. Matrix on - Math & Theology, 1960-1982 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Various MG notes on theology, etc, for Matrix column
      "Godel and God", by Andrew Riley, 11pp, 1978 (typescript)
    - Presidential Elections, 1959-2000 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      Notes, letters, articles, etc. on President facts
      "History Computed", by Arthur Finnessey, 1983, 24pp, 3 1/2 x 5 1/2 inches (pamphlet)
    - Matrix Release - on Garrison, 1967-1971 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      Jim Garrison's numerology on Kennedy's assisination
    - Press REleases on Dr. Matrix - Presidential Cand. Names, 1967-1968 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      Mostly press release on 1968 presidential candidates - Rockefeller, Romney, Reagan, Buckley, Shirley Temple (several copies), and comments on it
    - Numbers (Misc), 1963-2002 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Notes & articles on numbers
      Book project on "gosh" numbers
  - Fermat's Last Theorem, 7 folder(s)
    - Fermat's Last Theorem, 1938-2000 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Much history.
      "On the Bounds of l in Fermat's Last Theorem", by Guy A.R. Guillotte, 1972 (typescript of lecture)
      "The Ripple in the Carpet, Fermat's Last Theorem, and Kasner's Kindergarden", by Herbert E. Salzer (typescript)
    - Crank Proofs, 1980-1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Several "proofs", two as booklets, and some letters claiming proofs.
    - The Flawed 1988 Proof of Fermat's Last, 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Yoichi Miyaoka's
    - Wile's Proof, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Many articles, mostly popular, on Wile's proof, then the gap, and finally the fix; also history of FLT.
      Some explanitory articles.
      Thurston, William
    - Vos Savant Flap, 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Much correspondance about MG endorsement of Vos Savant book, and MG embarrassment over it.
      Also reviews and discussion of the book itself and the Parade column.
      Goldberg, Steven
      Huges, Brian
      Mazur, Barry
    - Beal's Problem, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      xm + yn = zr has no whole number solutions where x, y, z have no common factor & m, n, r are greater than 2.
      Single article (from Math Horizens) by Keith Devlin
      Beal, Andrew
    - E-Mail on FLT, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Much e-mail on vos Savant plus a couple of other photocopies, collected and sent to MG by Jerry Farrell.
  - Fractals & Chaos, 14 folder(s)
    - Fractals - & Mandelbrot [1 of 3], 1979-1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Many articles from popular science magazines.
    - Fractals - & Mandelbrot [2 of 3], 1967-1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      More articles and reviews.
      Selected bibliography (1988)
    - Fractals - & Mandelbrot [3 of 3], 1988-2000 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Eaton, Leonard
    - "Eternity Patterns" (Infinite Regress), 1973-2000 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      "Criss-Cross Communications", Number One, 1974 (magazine) with tipped-in photos & silkscreens.
      Yanoff, Michael
    - Snow Crystals, 1973-1987 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Chaos Theory [1 of 3], 1975-1987 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Many articles, popular & technical.
    - Chaos Theory [2 of 3], 1987-1993 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Journal of Chaos and Graphics, Vol. 2, Aug, 1987, Ed. by Clifford Pickover.
    - Chaos Theory [3 of 3], 1987-1998 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Amygdala [1 or 2], 1987-1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Issues 1-19
    - Amygdala [2 or 2], 1987-1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Slides from Amygdals issues (incomplete).
    - Fractal Rep-Tiles (Ammann), 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      16 Examples.
    - Pickover's Work (Chaos), 1987-1992 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Pickover, Clifford
    - Mandelbrot Set, 1985-1999 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Many articles and ads
      "Six Worlds" (in Turbo Pascal): Dysan 5 inch floppy disk
    - Quasi-Fractals (TTT & Sheffer Stroke), 2000 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      1 article, by Ian Stewart, from S.A. Aug, 2000.
  - Game Problems, 9 folder(s)
    - Shannon Switches, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      1 article (by Mansfield)
    - Klemperer's Games (Chess Tracks), 1948-1983 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Klemperer, Wolfgang
      Bolbus, Leonard
    - Glass's Toroidal TTT (& Peak, Pass, Deep Theorem), 11972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      "A Combinatorial Analogue of the Poincare Index Theorem", by Leon Glass, 1973 (typescript)
      Glass, Leon
    - Near-Sighted Hunter, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Reynolds, Robert
    - Conway's "Sylver Coinage" Game, 1966-1987 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Beanstalk & Conway's Beans-Don't-Talk, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Article by Guy
    - Take-Away (Nim-like) Games [1 of 3], 1955-1976 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Many examples, much analysis
      McAllister, Stephen
      Filman, Robert
      Cook, R.S.
      Mertz, Robert
    - Take-Away (Nim-like) Games [2 of 3], 1967-1986 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Melf, Frank
      Lenstra, H.W.
      Sibert, William
    - Take-Away (Nim-like) Games [3 of 3], 1982-2000 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Game Theory, 8 folder(s)
    - Parrando's Paradox, 1980? (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Single newspaper article
    - Prisoner's Dilemma, 1967-2000 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Verhoeff, Tom
    - Game Theory, 1955-2000 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Simple Games To Which Game Theory Applies, 1959-1995 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Riker, William
    - Game Theory Applications in S.S. & Ethics, 1954-1982 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      (S.S. = Social Sciences)
    - Games & Anthropology, 1959-1970 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Roberts, John
    - Decision Theory, 1953-2000 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      Dollar auction
      Supermarket paradox
      Prisoners Dilemma
      4 papers by Maya Bar-Hillel & Ruma Falk (1978-1980)
      Lyons
    - Penny Pinch Paradox, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Graphs, 26 folder(s)
    - Digraphs (Directed), 1959-1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Directed graphs - MG notes.
      "Equivalence of Topological Markov Shifts", by Ray Adlar et.al. (typescript).
      "Networks of Sounds: Graph Theory Applied to Studying Rhymes", by James Joyce (typescript)
      "Oedipus Loves His Mother", by Frank Harary, 1979 (typescript)
      Adler, Ray
    - Parallel Climbers, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Single article by Alan Tucker
    - Graphs, 1935-2002 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      "One Dimensional Analysis Situs", by James Singer, Galois Lecture, 1935 (copy)
      Many articles, notes, problems, etc.
      "A Telephone Dialing Question", by Benjamin Schwartz, 1992 (typescript)
      Ragland, Earl
    - Path Tracing Puzzles, 1961-1999 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Many puzzles.
      Sam Loy's Chines Puzzles (Sam Loyd?) - from newpaper.
    - Hamiltonian Paths & Circuits, 1960-1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Mostly MG notes.
    - My Hypercube Hamiltonian Path Puzzle, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      "The Spelling Superbee"
    - Graph Induction Program, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      INGRID: A Software Tool for Extremal Graph Theory; Research by Ronald Dutton & Robert Brigham (Primer and Users manual, and a compilation of results from the program.)
    - Utilities Problem, 1975-1979 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Water, Gas, and Electricity problem (K3,3).
      Mostly trying to track down the history of this problem.
    - Signed & Marked Graphs & Nets, 1977-1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      3 articles & pre-prints, by Frank Harary & others.
    - Perfect Tree Problem (Leech), 1974-1978 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Packing Trees in Complete Graphs, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Single typescript about packing sequential stars & paths into a complete graph, by Honsberger.
    - Left-Right Paths, 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Analysis by Joseph Malkevitch, and another by H. Shank
      Malkevitch, Joseph
    - Map Coloring of Independent Notes (or edges), 1962-1997 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Much Minty correspondence and papers, and some of his comments on other graph theorists.
      Minty, George
    - Graph Coloring, 1961-1996 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      3 papes (preprints) form Academy of Science of USSR, Siberian Branch, Institute of Mathematics, 1976: GT-5, GT-6, GT-7.
      Game of Exchange.
      White, Neil
    - Reconstruction Conjecture, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
      1 jpage MG notes.
    - Fraenkel's Directed Graph Games [1 of 2], 1974-1977 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      Many papers by Aviezri Fraenkel, on games and their analysis.
      Traffic Jam Games.
    - Fraenkel's Directed Graph Games [2 of 2], 1974-1984 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      More papers.
      Cannibals
      Arrows
      The Particles & Antiparticles Game
    - Rectangular Maps, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      1 article, by Colin Bell
    - Blanche Descartes, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Bibliography of her work
      "The Twelve Coin Problem", a poem
    - Harmonious Graphs, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      1 article, by Ron Graham & Neil Sloane
    - Slope Problems (Rob Jameson, Clemson), 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)